RAHUL NARODE

Chh.Sambhaji Nagar., Maharashatra, India | 9503881203 | naroderahul2002@gmail.com | Linkedin | Github | GFG | Certificates

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, Python, C, MySQL, JavaScript, JSON, CSS

Frameworks: ReactJS, Django, MVC, jQuery, Node.js, Flask, Streamlit, ExpressJS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS

DataBase: MYSQL and DBMS

Developers Tools and Administrator: VS Code, Google Cloud, AWS CLOUD, Git-Github, API

Course Work: SDLC (Software Engineerring), Cloud Computing, OOPS

ACHIEVMENTS

Resolved over 500 challenges across diverse coding platform, showcasing a breadth of problem-solving expertise

Secured an impressive Rank 8 on GFG, demonstrating mastery in solving 200+ problems with strategic insights.

Participant of Google Ready Facilitator Program

Participated and Contributed Ideas in the Walmart Sparkathon

Participated in GSSOC (GirlScript Summer of Code)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front End Developer Intern | Yeshshree Press Comps Pvt. Ltd. | (Onsite)

March 2023 - July 2023

- Developed a dashboard for employee management using Python-Django and Cassandra.
- Optimized employee management processes, resulting in a 20% improvement in efficiency.
- Automated employee check-ins using a REST API with Python and Flutter.
- Collaborated with the software development team to integrate the dashboard with existing systems.

Front End Developer Intern | IBM - SKILLBUILD | (REMOTE)

June 2023 - July 2023

- Creation of Clone Website i.e. Spotify Clone I have been design for the people who enjoy the fill of the Spotify clone.
- This internship was conducted in collaboration with IBM and the Edunet Foundation.
- Gained hands-on experience with front-end development and user interface design.

PROJECTS

Online Notes Sharing Website | Python, Django, SQL, HTML, CSS, PHP, Git Youtube Link

- An online platform for students to share and access educational notes.
- Designed and developed the front-end and back-end of the website.
- Implemented user authentication, file uploads, and search functionality.
- Deployed the project using GitHub and managed the codebase using Git.

- Create M2M (Minutes of Meeting | Python, Machine Learning (Basics), NLP, Google API's, |

 Developed M2M (Minutes to Meeting) application to transcribe audio files into text and generate summarized outputs in different languages.
 - Utilized machine learning and natural language processing techniques, leveraging Google APIs for accurate transcription
 - Takes audio/video input from the user and provides a summarized output.

E-Commerce Website (MERN Stack) | React JS, MongoDB, Express, Node JS, HTML, CSS Youtube Link

- Developed a fully responsive online store to enhance user experience across devices.
- Designed and implemented the front-end using React JS, featuring product display, shopping cart functionality, and user authentication (login/registration).
- Built a scalable back-end with Node.js, Express, and MongoDB to manage APIs for product management (add, update, display), user authentication, and cart functionality.
- Developed an admin panel for product management, allowing easy product updates and additions..

Hand Gesture Controlled Gaming Experience | Python, OpenCV, CV zone, pynput Youtube Link

COURSES AND CERTIFICATION

MySQL Certificate | Cert.ID:UC-c36c9cee-bb3b-49e0-ac1c-9c558bf70414

Amcat Certified Software Trainee (Cert.ID: 418060324189993)

Oracle Certified Foundations Associate (Cert.ID: 1003095620CIF2023CA)

Infosys- Web-Design Begins with HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Google Cloud (Certificate ID: 19854-18719505-1016) | Google Cloud Profile | Profile Link

EDUCATION

Deogiri Institute of Engineering & Management Studies B.Tech in Computer Science | CGPA: 7.25 January 2020 - August 2024 Chhatrapati Shahu College, Lasur Station **HSC-Science** | Precentage : 60.92 August 2018 - May 2020 DCA ,Chh.Sambhaji Nagar. **SSC** | Percentage: 60.00 July 2018

EXTRA CURRICULAR